Staff / Principal Software Engineer

Profile

I am a software engineer with 18 years of experience building tech solutions across several industries and a strong entrepreneurial focus. I am equally comfortable with hands-on delivery (i.e. writing code) and managing engineering teams (i.e. helping other developers write code). I help organisations embrace new technologies to solve challenging real-world problems and launch successful products that customers love.

Work experience

Principal/Founding Software Engineer for an early stage start-up

Motif, London, United Kingdom – October 2023 until now (motifgroup.co)

ightarrow Responsible for API-as-a-product applications in the connected packaging sphere.

Reporting directly to the managing director. Building a greenfield API-as-a-product focusing on intelligent packaging. Building PoCs for clients. Defining ways of working & software development lifecycle. <u>Technology:</u> AWS, TypeScript, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), CDK, Docker, MySQL, Prisma, Redis, SQS.

.

Lead Software Engineer (contract-based), London, UK - Jul 2019 to September 2023

- → **Flowtrace**, UK-based company metrics tool provider Feb. to Sep. 2023 (<u>flowtrace.co</u>) Built new third-party data provider integrations for feeding into the core SaaS tool.
- → **Bulb Energy,** UK-based green energy provider Mar. to Nov. 2022 (<u>bulb.co.uk</u>) via <u>YLD.io</u> Built & improved comms features for rolling out electric smart meter installations across the business.
- → **Condé Nast,** global publishing house Mar. to Dec. 2021 (<u>condenast.com</u>) via <u>YLD.io</u>
 Built an internal API & validation library for content migration of 50 publications to a new tech stack.
- → **Progressive Content,** marketing agency Sep. 2020 to Feb. 2021 (<u>progressivecontent.com</u>) Built a microservices backend for a UK-based banking client's content marketing CMS.
- → **AND Digital,** software consultancy Jul. 2019 to Apr. 2020 (and.digital)

 Led a development team of 5 members in a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

<u>Technology:</u> Node.js, Serverless, TypeScript, GraphQL, React, Docker, Kubernetes, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch, Github Actions, AWS, GCP, Azure, Terraform

•

Head of Engineering / Tech Lead for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for an API-as-a-product, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures. Led technical team (8 members between UK and Poland). Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.

<u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible.

Mentoring, since 2017

- → Since 2024 MentorCruise: Mentoring on system design, software engineering, career orientation.
- → Since 2023 GDG Academy program: Mentoring students in various UK universities.
- \rightarrow 2017-2022 Open Classrooms: Tutoring for the tech lead curriculum for a french online education platform.

Technical Lead for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (jamieoliver.com)

Managed 3 contractors. Lead a migration from a legacy SOAP CRM to a microservices architecture.

<u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Team Leader / Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components Worked with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Led the delivery of news publishing apps. Managed activities' budgets. Spoke at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries) Oversaw the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, and agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap.

<u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - Mar. 2009 to Mar. 2015 (internews.org)

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications and custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Deployment and monitoring of secure hosting & video platforms. Facilitating training: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).

Technology: Drupal, WordPress, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Vagrant, Nginx, Linux administration

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (hellotipi.com)

Technology: MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeq, Debian, Linux administration

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

Junior Software Engineer for e-training IT projects for an international training centre Valeo Thermal Systems Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course support creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (esiea.fr)

 \rightarrow Graduated with first-class honours.

Foreign languages

Arabic: Beginner French: Mother tongue English: Fluent **Spanish:** Basic level

Hobbies

Curating a weekly music newsletter. Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. Photography (film and digital).

Part of the media team of a <u>non-league fan-owned football club</u> in East London.